BRYAN PEARSON

PERSONAL INFORMATION

University: University of Central Florida

College Unit: College of Engineering and Computer Science (CECS)

Address: HPA1-111, University of Central Florida

Email: bpearson@knights.ucf.edu

BIOGRAPHY

Bryan Pearson joined the Department of Computer Science at the University of Central Florida as a Ph.D student in August 2018, under the supervision of Dr. Xinwen Fu. He received his B.S. in Computer Science from Stetson University (2014), with minors in Physics and Mathematics.

Bryan's research interests include security and forensics of wireless sensor networks (WSN) and Internet of Things (IoT) systems, networking quality of service (QoS), and IoT scalability. He has been publishing in several conferences and journals including IEEE International Conference on Communications, SoutheastCon, INFOCOM, and MDPI Sensors.

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida

August 2018 - Present

Ph.D in Computer Science

Focus: Internet of Things (IoT) security Advisors: Dr. Cliff Zou & Dr. Xinwen Fu

Stetson University

May 2018 GPA: 3.507 / 4.000

B.S. in Computer Science Minors in Math and Physics Advisor: Dr. Daniel Plante

RESEARCH INTERESTS

- IoT security and forensics
- Applications and solutions of WSN and IoT
- Networking and computer systems QoS
- Light cryptography implementation and optimizations

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Assistant August 2018 - Present

Florida IT Pathways to Success (Flit-Path)

Graduate Research Assistant

August 2018 - August 2019

University of Central Florida, Department of Computer Science

Instructor June 2017 - July 2018

ID Tech Camps

Clerical Assistant

May 2017 - June 2018

Stetson University, Departments of English/Computer Science

SCHOLARSHIPS AND GRANTS

University of Central Florida

Graduate Presentation Fellowship

IEEE ICC NSF Student Travel Grant

Graduate Presentation Fellowship

Graduate Presentation Fellowship

February 2019

Graduate ORC Doctoral Fellowship

Flit-Path NSF Grant

August 2018

August 2018

Stetson University

Presidential Scholarship
Federal Pell Grant
August 2014 - May 2018
Bright Futures FASA
August 2014 - May 2018
August 2014 - May 2018

ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

Committee Membership 1. Program Committee, Consortium for Computing Sciences in Colleges (CCSC SE) 2. Web Chair (Organizing Committee), SecureComm 2019 Refereed Journal Papers 1. IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IoT-J) 2. IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IoT-J) 2020 Refereed Conference Papers 1. IEEE International Conference on Parallel and Distributed Systems (ICPADS) 2020

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. B. Pearson, D. Plante. Secure Deployment of Containerized IoT Systems. *In proceedings of IEEE South-eastCon 2020*. Raleigh, North Carolina. Mar. 2020.
- 2. Y. Zhang, J. Weng, Z. Ling, B. Pearson, X. Fu. BLESS: A BLE Application Security Scanning Framework. In proceedings of IEEE INFOCOM 2020 IEEE Conference on Computer Communications (INFOCOM). Beijing, China. Apr. 2020.
- 3. B. Pearson, L. Luo, C. Zou, J. Brian, Y. Jin, X. Fu. Building a Low-cost and State-of-the-art IoT Security Hands-on Laboratory. 2nd IFIP Internation Internet of Things (IoT) Conference. Oct. 31-Nov. 1, 2019. (Invited Paper.)
- 4. C. Gao, L. Luo, Y. Zhang, B. Pearson, X. Fu. Microcontroller Based IoT System Firmware Security: Case Studies. *In proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Industrial Internet (ICII)*, Orlando, FL, Nov. 2019. (Best Paper Award.)
- B. Pearson, L. Luo, Y. Zhang, R. Dey, Z. Ling, M. Bassiouni, and X. Fu. On Misconception of Hardware and Cost in IoT Security and Privacy. In proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC), Shanghai, China, May 2019.
- 6. L. Luo, Y. Zhang, B. Pearson, Z. Ling, H. Yu, and X. Fu. On the Security and Data Integrity of Low-Cost Sensor Networks for Air Quality Monitoring. *Sensors (Basel)*. Dec. 2018.
- N. Domingo, B. Pearson, and Y. Jin. Exploitations of Wireless Interfaces Via Network Scanning. In proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Computing, Networking and Communications (ICNC), Santa Clara, CA, 2017.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C, Python, Java, R, PHP, JavaScript, MatLab

2. Consortium for Computing Sciences in Colleges (CCSC SE)

Software: Arduino IDE, ESP-IDF, MatLab, Splunk, Wireshark, Mongoose OS, AWS, Google Cloud, Microsot Azure, Node.js, Apache, Nginx, Spark, Docker, Kubernetes

REFERENCES

Dr. Xinwen Fu (Primary Advisor)

Associate Professor of Computer Science

Email: xinwenfu@ucf.edu

2020

Dr. Cliff Zou (Co-advisor)

Associate Professor of Computer Science

Email: changchun.zou@ucf.edu

University of Central Florida